There's a lot of excitement right now
现在有很多振奋人心的消息
around the record speed vaccines for COVID-19
比如以创纪录速度研制的新冠疫苗
some of which are already starting distribution in parts of the world
其中一些已经开始在世界各地开始销售
But given that these are mRNA vaccines
但是他们都是mRNA(信使核糖核酸)疫苗
are relatively new technology
是非常新的技术
that has not been widely used before
是之前没有被大范围应用的技术
we wanted to explain how they work and what happens to your body
所以我们想要向大家解释他们如何在你的身体里发挥作用
from the moment that needle touches your skin
还有当针头触碰到你身体的那一刻，你的身体会进行怎样的变化
like vaccines, we're used to seeing these vaccines
对于疫苗，我们以前所接触到的疫苗都是这样
will be injected into the upper muscle of your arm
注射到你的手臂上层肌肉的疫苗
but unlike typical vaccines
但是不同于典型的疫苗
which introduce inactive or weakened forms of a virus
注入不活跃或者被削弱的病毒
these will release genetic material called Messenger RNA
新的疫苗会释放那些被称为mRNA(信使核糖核酸)的遗传物质
So what exactly does this mRNA do?
所以mRNA(信使核糖核酸)具体是干什么的呢?
well, in regular cell of your body
好的，在你身体里的正常细胞里
you have DNA inside of the nucleus and this DNA stores
有在细胞核内的DNA(脱氧核糖核酸)
all the information and instructions important
并且在DNA(脱氧核糖核酸)里储藏着所有的重要信息
to the functioning of your cells your body
还有对于帮助你身体正常运转的细胞的指令
and ultimately makes you you
这所有最终成就了你
inside your cell is machinery that reads through your DNA
在你的细胞里有一个机器将会读取你的DNA(脱氧核糖核酸)
and transcribes it into mRNA
然后将它转录成mRNA(信使核糖核酸)
which then leaves the nucleus and goes into your cytoplasm
在这之后mRNA(信使核糖核酸)将会离开细胞核进入细胞质
And it's here that the ribosomes
在这里的核糖体
and yourselves read the RNA
将会读取RNA(核糖核酸)
and depending on the specific code to build a series of amino acids
之后依靠确切的编码构建出一系列的氨基酸
which fold in on themselves to make proteins
这些会折叠形成蛋白质
which keep you alive and functioning
它们会发挥作用从而使你继续活着
This process is known as translation
这个过程就被称为翻译
In fact, it's this process that viruses take advantage of in the first place
实际上，这也是病毒首先利用的过程
They insert their own genetic information into you
他们将自己的遗传信息嵌入你的体内
and then your cell machinery unwittingly starts taking
然后你的细胞机器糊里糊涂地开始复制这些信息
that information and building proteins to help create more viruses
之后构建出能够创造更多病毒的蛋白质
So back to the needle
因此让我们重新回到针头这里
the mRNA that is being injected into you
在疫苗中的mRNA(信使核糖核酸)也会携带遗传指令
from the vaccine also carries genetic instructions
跟随针头一起被注射进你的身体
but in this case, it's only coding
但是在这种情况下，它只是
for one small part of the virus
很小一部分的病毒
instead of the whole thing
而不是病毒整体
You're probably seen SARS-CoV-2 represented like this
你可能见过带着S蛋白的
with the spikes on it
SARS-CoV-2(新型冠状病毒)
And it's this spike protein which on its own is harmless
它所携带的S蛋白本身是对人体无害
that the vaccines mRNA codes for
这也是mRNA(信使核糖核酸)疫苗的编码
The mRNA makes its way into the cytoplasm of your cells
mRNA(信使核糖核酸)进入你的细胞质
where the ribosomes read the information
也就是核糖体读取信息的地方
and start to create the spike proteins
然后开始构建S蛋白
Once the protein is made
一旦蛋白质形成
it goes to the cell membrane and then your cell breaks down
它会进入细胞膜，然后你的细胞就崩溃了
and destroys the injected mRNA instructions
还会破坏被注射的mRNA(信使核糖核酸)的指令
So what good does having a tiny fragment of viral spike in your body do?
所以你身体中这一个微小的病毒片段有什么好处呢?
Well, it gives your body and more importantly
嗯，它会给你的身体，主要是你的免疫系统
your immune system, a preview of what the virus looks like
提前的一个病毒预演
without causing disease
不会引起任何疾病的预演
Suddenly your antibodies will notice it and go
然后你的抗体就会突然意识到
well, this doesn't belong here
“嗯，这个东西不属于这”
which triggers an immune response to recognize
之后就会触发你的免疫反应进行识别
and prepare your body for the real thing
帮助你的身体准备好应对真正的病毒
without ever having to come in contact
在不必要接触
with the actual virus itself
真正病毒的情况下
Your immune system essentially gets a headstart
这样你的免疫系统基本上就已经领先一步了
by creating powerful antibodies that can neutralize
通过创造有效抗体来中和
and kill the real virus
或者杀死真正的病毒
And this antibody memory is stored in your B cells
并且这个抗体记忆将会被储存在你的B淋巴细胞中
so that if you are ever infected in the future
以便应对将来如果你被感染了
with the SARS-CoV-2 virus, your body now has the upper hand
SARS-CoV-2(新型冠状病毒)，你的身体将会占据上风
This is known as an adaptive immune response
这就是适应性免疫反应
Your body has already seen these spike proteins before
你的身体之前已经见过S蛋白了
and therefore it already knows what to do
所以它已经知道再见到S蛋白它该如何应对了
Essentially, these mRNA vaccines allow your body
更重要的是，这些mRNA(信使核糖核酸)能够
to protect itself from a future infection
让你的身体能在未来被感染时也能保护你
without ever having to risk the consequences of getting the disease COVID-19
而不必冒着感染COVID-19(新型冠状肺炎)的风险
So why haven't mRNA vaccines been used before?
所以为什么mRNA(信使核糖核酸)疫苗之前不被使用?
While they are relatively new
尽管它是相对较新的
researchers have actually been experimenting with them for decades
但是研究人员已经研究他们长达几十年了
but in the past they've been very unstable
他们在过去一直都非常的不稳定
Enzymes in your body would break down the mRNA quickly
因为你体内的酶会将mRNA(信使核糖核酸)迅速分解
so they needed to be packaged well
所以mRNA(信使核糖核酸)需要被包裹起来
The ones being released now have the mRNA encased
现在被释放进身体的已经将mRNA(信使核糖核酸)
in lipid nanoparticles which essentially protect
用能够很好保护mRNA(信使核糖核酸)不被降解的
the mRNA from being degraded
脂质纳米粒包裹起来了
Since there are more unstable than other types of vaccines
因为mRNA(信使核糖核酸)疫苗比起其他疫苗来说
they have to be kept cold
非常不稳定，所以它需要冷藏保存
For example, the Pfizer vaccine
例如，辉瑞疫苗
it has to be stored at minus 70 degrees Celsius
它需要储藏在零下70摄氏度的环境
and at normal refrigerated temperatures
在正常冷藏温度下
can only last five days
只能储藏五天
Of course, a global pandemic has certainly increased
当然，全球的疫情将会让
the funding and resources going towards
更多的资金和资源
these types of vaccines which has helped
流向这些类型疫苗
to accelerate their development
从而加快它们的研究进程
What makes these vaccines so appealing
是什么让这些疫苗如此吸引人
is that unlike other vaccines
是不同于其他疫苗吗?
they can be made in a lab with readily available materials
是因为它们可以用实验室现成的材料制造
and actually made much quicker than other types of vaccines
并且能比其他疫苗制造起来快得多
Instead of fully developing non-infectious viruses
因为它不是完全发展出非传染性病毒
and then injecting them
然后注射
these mRNA vaccines can sort of pass many hurdles
这些mRNA(信使核糖核酸)疫苗可以越过很多障碍
by using your own body in an ingenious way
通过巧妙地运用你的身体
It's also far more cost-effective to create mRNA molecules
不同于直接制造蛋白质，制造mRNA(信使核糖核酸)的
rather than the proteins themselves
成本效益也同样高得多
and also a lot more scalable
而且更大的可扩展性
which is helpful when we are in a global pandemic waiting for a vaccine
将会切实帮助到我们目前全球疫情等待疫苗的状况
So is it safe?
所以它安全吗?
And given that it's a relatively new technology
考虑到它是一个相对较新的技术
should you be concerned at all?
你应该担心吗?
Well, that's what these initial trial stages have been for
好吧，这就是初审阶段的目的
Not only to test whether or not they work
不仅是去测试它是否能够有效地进行免疫反应
and cause immunity but to make sure
还要去确保
they have minimal side effects
最小的副作用
As for now around 70000 people
截止目前，已经大约有70000人
新辉瑞疫苗结果显示近95%有效
have been given these vaccines with no serious concerns
接种了疫苗，并且没有严重的问题
新辉瑞疫苗结果显示近95%有效
辉瑞新冠疫苗95%有效且安全，超过预期
a caveat being that the full research
但是请注意截至本视频录制之前
辉瑞新冠疫苗95%有效且安全，超过预期
辉瑞新冠疫苗在65岁以上人群中“94%”有效
hasn't been published yet as of recording this video
所有的研究成果还未正式公布
辉瑞新冠疫苗在65岁以上人群中“94%”有效
辉瑞新冠疫苗结果：安全且95%有效
But it's important to remember that just because it's safe doesn't mean
但是很重要的一点是明白，它的安全
there won't be any soreness or pain
并不意味着它不会让你感到疼痛
Some recipients did report aches and pains
一些接种者可能会感到疼痛
and as of now you'll need to receive two shots to ensure efficacy
并且从现在起你必须接种两针才能保证疗效
I saw a really great analogy by the professor Shane Crotty
我看到一个来自从事疫苗研究谢恩·克罗蒂教授的
who works in vaccine research and he said
很恰当的比喻
It's not unlike going to the gym and getting exercise
这和你去健身房锻炼
and really sore muscles
之后肌肉酸痛没什么区别
a bit of pain can be a positive sign
一点疼痛是一个好的信号
that good things are happening
证明一些好的事情正在发生
Sometimes you have to earn your immunity
有时候你必须获得免疫力
just like you have to earn those biceps you wanted so bad
就像你必须要获得你想要的的二头肌一样
We know you've been asking about these vaccines a lot
我们知道你已经提出了很多对于疫苗的疑问
we've also had our questions
同样我们也有自己的问题
So we hope that all this information was useful
所以我们希望所有信息对大家是有效的
and concise and educational for you
简单的同时有能够让大家明白
cause it does sort of help make things
因为这真的有助于
seem less unknown and scary in a very strange time
让那些陌生的东西不再那么陌生可怕
Thank you all so much for watching
衷心感谢您的收看